In life we have responsibilities things that we need to take care of.
在生活中，我们有责任需要照顾的事情。
If you do all of your responsibilities very well then people may say that you're very responsible.
如果你把所有的责任都做好了，那么人们可能会说你很负责任。
That's the kind of person you are.
你就是这样的人。
You're a responsible person.
你是一个负责任的人。
OK.
好的。
But what phrases or words can we use to explain our responsibilities to others.
但是我们可以用什么短语或词语来向他人解释我们的责任。
Well there are a couple that are very common and I want to go through those because when you're talking
嗯，有一些很常见，我想看看那些，因为当你说话的时候
about your routine or when you're describing to others what you do or maybe you're telling others what
关于你的日常生活，或者当你向别人描述你在做什么，或者你在告诉别人什么
they need to do you may need to use these phrases.
他们需要做你可能需要使用这些短语。
OK.
好的。
So first one I'm in charge of.
所以我负责的第一个。
And then we could say either a noun or an action and we can use ISG after it.
然后我们可以说一个名词或一个动作，我们可以在它之后使用 ISG。
So we could say I'm in charge of interviews about that son and I eat us interviews in the H R department
所以我们可以说我负责那个儿子的采访，我在人力资源部门吃我们的采访
H.R. stands for by the way human resources are.
HR代表人力资源的方式。
Yes human resources.
是的人力资源。
I'm responsible for interviews in human resources or I'm in charge of interviews in the human resources
我负责人力资源的面试或者我负责人力资源的面试
or H.R. department.
或人力资源部门。
OK.
好的。
You could also though say I'm in charge of making sure that we deliver everything on time.
你也可以说我负责确保我们按时交付所有东西。
Whatever you're doing you can say making sure I'm in charge of making sure that something happens.
无论你在做什么，你都可以说确保我负责确保某事发生。
Whatever it is.
不管是什么。
So it's a very useful phrase to explain the thing that you need to do.
所以这是一个非常有用的短语来解释你需要做的事情。
It's your responsibility.
这是你的责任。
You're in charge of doing.
你负责做。
I Angie that thing.
我安吉那个东西。
But we could also say need I'm sure you probably know this one but I need to make sure.
但我们也可以说需要，我相信你可能知道这个，但我需要确定。
So it's sort of like making sure same thing.
所以这有点像确保同样的事情。
I need to make sure I need to make sure that we follow all the regulations.
我需要确保我需要确保我们遵守所有规定。
Regulations are like rules regulations are like sometimes laws whatever I need to make sure it's the
法规就像规则 法规有时就像法律 我需要确保它是
same as saying I'm in charge of making sure you can use either one it doesn't really matter.
就像说我负责确保您可以使用其中任何一个都没关系。
I need to make sure that we follow all the regulations.
我需要确保我们遵守所有规定。
I'm in charge of making sure we follow all the regulations when problems happen.
我负责确保我们在出现问题时遵守所有规定。
If you're responsible for the action that needs to be taken when that problem happens we can go back
如果您对发生该问题时需要采取的措施负责，我们可以返回
to that word that we mentioned before whenever.
对于我们之前提到的那个词。
Again that means every time so we could say whenever there are delays delays means something is not
同样，这意味着每次，所以我们可以说，只要有延误，延误就意味着没有
on time something is a little a little late.
准时的事情有点晚了。
Whenever there are delays it's my fault.
每次延误都是我的错。
It's that's an S.
就是那个S。
Can you imagine.
你可以想象。
That's an s it's my job it's my job to maybe push the team push the team to hit the deadline.
那是我的工作，也许推动团队推动团队赶上最后期限是我的工作。
L I N E hit the deadline.
L I N E 赶上了最后期限。
OK so here's a team.
好的，这里有一个团队。
This team has to do some work.
这个团队必须做一些工作。
Maybe the team is making a video.
也许团队正在制作视频。
OK.
好的。
And there are delays because maybe one person is sick.
并且有延误，因为也许一个人生病了。
So the whole team is a little bit late.
所以整个团队有点晚了。
OK.
好的。
Whenever there are delays whenever that thing happens for whatever reason whose job is it to deal with
每当那件事发生时，无论出于何种原因，都需要处理延误
this problem.
这个问题。
It's my job it's my job I'm responsible for it I'm responsible for making sure we hit the deadline.
这是我的工作，这是我的工作，我对此负责，我有责任确保我们按时完成。
I need to make sure we hit the deadline.
我需要确保我们赶上最后期限。
It's my job to push the team to hit the deadline or we could say to make the deadline.
我的工作是推动团队赶上最后期限，或者我们可以说赶上最后期限。
So this is the one that you would use when you want to explain what you're responsible for whenever
所以当你想解释你的责任时，你会使用这个
X happens.
X 发生。
Whatever it is when we're talking about our responsibilities we also need to talk about consequences
不管是什么，当我们谈论我们的责任时，我们也需要谈论骗局序列
consequences.
结果。
What happens if something bad happens.
如果发生不好的事情会发生什么。
What happens maybe if something good happens.
如果有好事发生，可能会发生什么。
These are consequences the result of something else.
这些是其他事情的结果。
OK.
好的。
So let's say if I don't finish don't finish my part.
所以让我们说，如果我没有完成我的部分。
Maybe everybody has a part let's say it's this video project we're trying to make a video for advertising
也许每个人都有一部分让我们说这是我们正在尝试制作广告视频的这个视频项目
or whatever.
管他呢。
If I don't finish my part the rest of the team maybe can't go home or the rest of the team has to work
如果我没有完成我的部分，团队的其他成员可能无法回家，或者团队的其他成员必须工作
overtime or the rest of the team will have to do my work for me whatever it is we're talking about what
加班或团队的其他成员将不得不为我做我的工作，无论我们在谈论什么
happens if this thing happens.
如果这件事发生，就会发生。
And it could be a good thing or a bad thing.
这可能是好事也可能是坏事。
OK.
好的。
Whenever we get an award the whole team gets to go up on stage not just me not just the leader.
每当我们获得奖项时，整个团队都会登上舞台，而不仅仅是我，而不仅仅是领导者。
So consequent These are the results and we can use this type of sentence this expression to explain
So consequent 这些就是结果，我们可以用这种类型的句子这个表达式来解释
the consequences of a specific thing that happens if I don't finish my part my job my responsibility.
如果我没有完成我的工作我的责任，那么发生的特定事情的后果。
Everybody needs to work overtime and then we have to pay everybody overtime and maybe we can't afford
每个人都需要加班，然后我们必须支付每个人的加班费，也许我们负担不起
that.
那。
Can't afford something means you don't have enough money to pay for it or you're just not able to pay
买不起东西意味着你没有足够的钱来支付它，或者你只是无法支付
for it.
为了它。
Maybe it's too much for you.
也许对你来说太多了。
We could have used that in the last lesson when we were talking about the apartment.
当我们谈论公寓时，我们可以在上一课中使用它。
I can't afford one thousand five hundred I can't afford it.
我买不起一千五百，我买不起。
It's out of my price range.
这超出了我的价格范围。
It's over my budget.
这超出了我的预算。
OK so let's now look at a real life example of a routine and how we can put all of these things together
好的，现在让我们看一个日常生活的例子，以及我们如何将所有这些东西放在一起
in a really natural way.
以一种非常自然的方式。